Ren Burnett

Adaptable fullstack developer with attention to detail and the ability to empathetically and thoughtfully collaborate. Excited to bring traits gained in six years as a precision technician to help shape quality code. Enthusiastic about learning new technologies/languages as well as developing helpful, practical software.

(206) 669-7498 renardburnett@gmail.com github.com/renburnett linkedin.com/in/renard-burnett-ii ren-burnett.azurewebsites.net

PROJECTS

GrocerySaver — Food Inventory Tracker

github.com/renburnett/grasher-app-frontend

React frontend, Ruby Rails backend, Semantic-React UI for styling

EXPERIENCE

Moby Inc., Fullstack Developer — Edmonds, WA mobyinc.com github.com/mobyinc

SEPTEMBER 2021 - CURRENT

Contributing to several different projects with a range of frameworks and backends, the most prominent including Vue.js, React and Angular. Our backends are typically written in PHP, Node.js or Ruby on Rails. Typically Craft CMS is used to set up client portals.

Center For Learning, React and Rails Developer — Irvine, CA c4lacademy.com

FEBRUARY 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

React/TypeScript frontend, Rails backend. Education application through which students can learn and acquire their High School diploma.

Banana App (BGP), React and Rails Developer — Seattle, CA github.com/FoodIsLifeBGP/banana-rn banana-app

JANUARY 2020 - JANUARY 2021

React Native frontend written in TypeScript, Rails backend. Contributed to Banana App code base. Banana App is an open-source, not-for-profit project of The Be Good Foundation. Aim is to reduce hunger by simplifying the food donation process.

Microsoft via WTIA, Software Developer Apprentice — Redmond

NOVEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Created a Bluetooth Radio Provisioning tool that is now used to set up mock peripherals for testing against the Windows OS for Bluetooth Quality Team. Reduced the time spent testing OS by one to two hours. Wrote a Python script that ran daily to scrape customer reviews from online stores; data was made actionable after it was visualized in PowerBI. During my time here, began teaching myself React.

Boeing, Composite Technician and Team Lead — Everett

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2017

Team leader of a fast-paced seven person Composite Repair Team. Interactions with teammates were professional, respectful and fun. Ensured that the majority of deadlines were met but not at expense of quality work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript / ES Next
React / React Native
Vue.js
Angular
HTML5 / CSS
Git
C#
Python
Ruby on Rails
MVC Architecture
SQL
Azure

EDUCATION

North Seattle College

WEB DEVELOPMENT | 2015 - 2019

Flatiron School — Software Engineering Certificate

DECEMBER 2019

TLG Learning — C# Developer Certificate

NOVEMBER 2017

 Learned how to leverage concepts such as inheritance, method overriding, interfaces, and object hierarchies in C# etc.